

ABEL C VARGHESE

My Contact

- □ abelcvarghese12097@gmail.com
- **(%)** 8301032838, 8075401483
- Cheriyakudiyil(H), Vadattupara, Kothamangalam
- https://jackiechaaan.github.io/A
 CVPortfolio/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/abe l-c-varghese

Hard Skill

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- React JS Basics
- Bootstrap 5, jQuery
- Responsive Design
- Python, PHP, C, C++,Core Java
- Spring, Servelet, MySQL, Eclipse, NetBeans

Soft Skill

- Team Work
- Dependability
- Hard Work
- Willingness to learn
- · Research and Integrity

Education Background

- Master of Computer Application (MCA)
 Mar Athanasius College, Kothamangalam
 2022 2024 76.30%
- Bachelor of Computer Application (BCA)
 Mount Carmel College, Kothamangalam
 Percentage 67.3%
 2015 2018
- Plus Two

St. Stephen's HSS, Keerampara Percentage - 78.33% 2013 - 2015

SSLC

GHS POIKA, Vadattupara Percentage - 93.33% 2013

About Me

MCA student with a passion for front-end technologies. I am a self-taught react js developer also having I year of experience as a data analyst with excel. Using my technical skills and creativity, I would like to work as a Front-end Developer to create websites that are responsive, user-friendly, and visually appealing.

Experience

MintMelon Business Consulting LLP | Data Analyst

Ernakulam, Kerala

Nov 2019 - Dec 2020

Key responsibilities:

- Analysis of data using MS Excel, for a US client.
- Preparation of documents and reports based on client requirements.

iROID Technologies Pvt.Ltd | Intern - Java

Ernakulam, Kerala

Oct 2018 - Mar 2019

Key responsibilities:

- Worked as Intern-Java Developer in Chemicals project
- REST API development with Spring framework

Self Taught Projects Experience:-

Personal Portfolio using React JS
 https://jackiechaaan.github.io/ACVPortfolio/

Experimental Training

Database Projects (BCA)

- Life Insurance Management System
- Online Voting System
- Monochrome Chemicals (Internship)

Machine Learning Project (MCA)

- Car Price Prediction using Machine Learning
- Cardio Vascular Disease (CVD) Prediction Using ML

Languages

- Malayalam (Native)
- English